# VY NGUYEN

## Web Developer

#### SUMMARY

Natural problem solver and quick learner with high attention to details. Passionate about writing clean and efficient code, developing solutions, and learning new technologies. Experience with working in a fast pace environment and having strong time management skills, great communication skills, and a positive attitude.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

React . React Native . Redux . AngularJS . JavaScript jQuery . HTML5 . CSS3 . Sass . Bootstrap . Reactstrap Flexbox . Pug . Drupal . Wordpress . PHP . Node.js . MySQL MongoDB . Loopback . Redis . Git . Github . Command Line Photoshop . Visual Studio Code . Xcode . Expo . FileZilla Jira . Bitbucket . Teamwork . Asana

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Arts in University Studies EAST TEXAS BAPTIST UNIVERSITY, MAY 2011

- + Magna Cum Laude, 3.7 GPA
- + Alpha Chi Honor Society & Dean's List with Honors

## Certification in Full Stack Web Development ORIGIN CODE ACADEMY, APR 2018

+ HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Redux, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Loopback, Redis, Command Line, Git, and more

#### LET'S WORK TOGETHER

Mobile: (619) 484-8576

Email: vy.t.nguyen.11@gmail.com

Website: vunit.io

Portfolio: vunit.io/portfolio Github: github.com/vunit2007 LinkedIn: in/vy-nguyen-715417102

Location: San Diego, CA

#### WORK HISTORY

### Web Developer

#### 101 NETWORK | SEPT 2019 - JAN 2020

- Utilize Wordpress, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, & CSS.
- Develop responsive and dynamic Wordpress websites that ensure high traffic and user-friendly experience.
- Ensure cross-browser, cross-platform, and multiple device type compatibility for all web solutions.
- Support operations team with day-to-day requests related to website functionality and performance.
- Involve in all aspects of the application development lifecycle: Idea, Development, QA, Documentation, Implementation, and Integration
- Develop, maintain, troubleshoot and enhance existing web applications and services.
- Adhere to project schedules and effectively report progress to meet challenging deadlines.
- · Code Review before merging into Github.

### Front-end Developer

#### TRAGIC MEDIA I OCT 2018 - APR 2019

- Took Photoshoop files from design and created responsive landing pages using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and Flexbox.
- Utilized Wordpress, Drupal, Filezilla, Photoshop, Git, Npm, and Gulp during production process.
- Worked closely with other developers in researching, implementing, testing, debugging, deploying, and maintaining web applications.
- Completed tasks using teamwork.com for agile/scrum development methodology.

## Software Developer Intern

#### NEWROCKET I AUG 2018 - SEPT 2018

 Helped troubleshoot widgets and service portals using the ServiceNow platform and utilizing AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, and Bootstrap.

### Software Developer Contractor

#### FICUS | Mar 2018 - May 2018

- Designed, built, tested, and deployed Ficus Mini, the beta edition to the gamified stock-trading Ficus app (available on iOS).
- Built the Ficus Mini app using React-Native for the front-end and MongoDB, Express, Redis, and Loopback for the backend.
- Utilized Xcode, Expo, and Photoshop.
- Completed tasks using Jira and BitBucket for agile/scrum development methodology.

#### Financial Professional

#### AXA ADVISORS, SCOTTRADE, JPMORGAN CHASE BANK | FEB 2012 - SEPT 2018

- Met with clients to discuss their short-term and longterm financial goals.
- Came up with solutions, strategies, and the right products to help clients achieve their financial objectives.